<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Azure Data Factory on Sreenivas R Angara</title>
    <link>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/tags/azure-data-factory/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Azure Data Factory on Sreenivas R Angara</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 18:25:18 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/tags/azure-data-factory/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Prompt Engineering - Productivity on Steriods</title>
      <link>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/promptenggprodboost/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 18:25:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/promptenggprodboost/</guid>
      <description>In my recent data engineering quest, I had to wrangle data from seven sources and fill our data warehouse using Azure Data Factory. The end result? Twenty-one pipelines doing a synchronized dance, populating twenty-six tables. Back in the pre-ChatGPT era, this Herculean task would&amp;rsquo;ve demanded three full-time heroes for six months. Enter ChatGPT: in just five months, with the power of 1.25 FTEs, Mission Accomplished.
But that&amp;rsquo;s not all! ChatGPT Playground&amp;rsquo;s prompts turned me into a coding sorcerer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>API Pagination in the wild</title>
      <link>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/apipagination/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 18:25:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/apipagination/</guid>
      <description>In the dynamic API economy, service providers acknowledge the crucial role of API monetization in creating revenue streams. APIs have evolved into the backbone of modern software development, facilitating seamless data exchange between applications. As their complexity and usage increase, the need for efficient data retrieval becomes paramount. Recognizing the symbiotic relationship between API monetization and effective data handling is key for service providers to navigate the evolving landscape successfully, ensuring not only a seamless user experience but also the maximization of revenue potential.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Data Factory Copy Activity: The Swiss Army Knife of Data Integration</title>
      <link>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/azurecopyactivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Aug 2023 18:25:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/azurecopyactivity/</guid>
      <description>Think of Azure Data Factory&amp;rsquo;s Copy Activity as the Swiss Army knife of data integration. Just as a Swiss Army knife combines various tools into one compact design, Copy Activity seamlessly combines multiple data integration functions into a single, powerful feature.
Versatility: Just like a Swiss Army knife&amp;rsquo;s ability to handle various tasks, Copy Activity connects to diverse data sources and destinations, whether they&amp;rsquo;re in the cloud or on-premises.
Efficiency: Like a Swiss Army knife&amp;rsquo;s efficiency in handling different tasks, Copy Activity streamlines data movement and transformation in a single step.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
