<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>jupyter on Sreenivas R Angara</title>
    <link>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara_beta1/tags/jupyter/</link>
    <description>Recent content in jupyter on Sreenivas R Angara</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 18:25:18 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara_beta1/tags/jupyter/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>MIT-GreatLearning Applied Data Science program Capstone Project</title>
      <link>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara_beta1/posts/mit_capstone/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 18:25:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara_beta1/posts/mit_capstone/</guid>
      <description>During my participation in the MIT-GreatLearning Applied Data Science Program, I experienced an intensive curriculum that encompassed diverse subjects such as Statistics, Python programming, Machine Learning, Neural Networks, and Recommendation Systems.
The culmination of the program was the Capstone project, which aimed to predict Loan Default. This involved crucial steps like Data Preparation, Exploratory Data Analysis, constructing models, and generating a comprehensive performance report for the various models employed.
The final outcome is a binary classification.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning - Key terms</title>
      <link>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara_beta1/posts/ml_key_terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2023 18:25:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara_beta1/posts/ml_key_terms/</guid>
      <description>During an interview process, interviewers generally ask and expect textbook definitions of basic terms. Interviewees, on the other hand must be prepared and answer them promptly. Lengthy and exploratory answers prevent interviewers from asking more probing questions.
I noticed this issue on a recent interview and not repeat this mistake.
Confidence Interval A confidence interval is a range of values around the point estimate, constructed so that this range will contain the population parameter with a certain degree of confidence, expressed in percentage terms.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
