<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>architecture on Sreenivas R Angara</title>
    <link>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/tags/architecture/</link>
    <description>Recent content in architecture on Sreenivas R Angara</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 18:25:18 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/tags/architecture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Digital Twins: Bridging the Physical and Virtual Worlds</title>
      <link>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/azuredigitaltwins/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2023 18:25:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/azuredigitaltwins/</guid>
      <description>In a world fueled by technology, the concept of Digital Twins has emerged as a groundbreaking bridge between the physical and digital realms. Imagine having a virtual counterpart for real-world objects, processes, or systems that mimics their behavior and characteristics in real time. This technology is not just about static models – it&amp;rsquo;s about creating dynamic, synchronized virtual entities that offer a wealth of benefits across industries.
Digital Twins rely on a mix of technologies like IoT, data analytics, machine learning, and cloud computing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azure Landscape</title>
      <link>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/azurelandscape/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 18:25:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/azurelandscape/</guid>
      <description>This powerpoint presentation of various tiers in Microsoft Azure Cloud implementation.
With the architecture in-place, I want to answer the question
&amp;ldquo;How can you leverage Generative AI to build and maintain this infrastructure?&amp;rdquo; This is an embedded Microsoft Office presentation, powered by Office. Full PowerPoint presentation</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WIP - API Management Concepts</title>
      <link>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/api_management/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 18:25:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/api_management/</guid>
      <description>WIP - Putting my thoughts together a future article on Azure API Management. Policies Authentication Policies Access Restriction Policy Caching Policy Cross Domain Policies Transformation Policies Advanced Policies
Microservice Microservices are fine grained loosely coupled services communicating through light-weight protocols. Azure functions versus Docker. Portability versus serverless
API Management API Mangagement is a process of creating and publishing web application programming interfaces. Enforce usage policies, control access and analyse usage statistics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>WIP - Application Platforms</title>
      <link>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/appcontainers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 May 2023 18:25:18 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cooolbabu.github.io/SreenivasAngara/posts/appcontainers/</guid>
      <description>WIP - A future article on Enterprise Application Platforms Platforms: JBoss, Microsoft Entity Framework Core, SpringBoot
Applications: Web apps, REST services, SOA, JMS messaging
Layers: Presentation layer, Buiness Layer, Database Layer (use mermaid.js for text to Illustration)
Key concepts: Dependency Injection: Promotes loose coupling .. examples ??? Aspect Orient Programming: Apply application wide services to an application in a declarative fashion Logging, Transactions, Security POJO - Plain Old java object</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
